PAUL OPMANN

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+372 56689 018

paul.opmann@gmail.com

paulopmann.com

Estonia, Tallinn

EXPERTISE

- Node.js, Next.js, Nest.js (TypeScript)
- SQL / NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis)
- AWS, Firebase, Google Cloud
- · Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ
- REST / GraphQL API
- Docker
- React, React Native (TypeScript)
- redux, jotai, zuztand
- · PostCSS / SCSS
- · Tailwind / styled-components
- webpack
- php, Go, Java, python, Rust

EDUCATION

BoS - Computer Science 2018-2023



Tallinn University of Technology



Korean

Estonia, Tallinn

LANGUAGES



Intermediate

ABOUT ME

I'm a seasoned full-stack web developer with 4+ years of experience in TypeScript, Node.js, Nest.js, Express, Next.js, React, Redux, Docker, SQL and NoSQL databases, AWS, Google Cloud and Firebase. I'm dedicated to staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies to provide the best possible solutions for my clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Lawato 2022/07-present

- Managed cloud infrastructure and optimized services to minimize costs. Designed,
- developed, and took part in the implementation of the architecture for the MVP of the SaaS

Full Stack Developer

Lumav Commerce [remote]

11/2021-11/2022

- Optimized the performance of existing PWA applications.
- Built custom functionality modules for Magento 2 powered e-commerce applications.
- Implemented new and adjusted existing features in accordance with client requirements, software specification and design.

Full Stack Developer

Havas Estonia Estonia, Tallinn

02/2021-06/2021

- Built and managed back-end microservices.
- Translated provided designs into UI elements.
- Engaged in the process of cross-platform mobile application development.

Full Stack Developer

Freelance [remote]

2020-present

- Consulted clients on the technical requirements and potential costs.
- Built custom page parsers for data export.
- Built custom automation scripts and browser extensions.
- Engaged in the development of software MVP as both FE and BE developer..

Back End Developer

Pipedrive

Estonia, Tallinn

08/2019-05/2020

- Built and managed back-end microservices.
- Leveraged Agile methodologies to move the development lifecycle rapidly through initial prototyping to enterprise-quality testing and final implementation. Took part in
- · the on-call rotation.
- · Created and managed existing APIs.